

About me

eb developer, having worked as an Architect for more than 10 years, has allowed me to develop skills in the field of design and user experience.

I'm passionate about programming and technology, I have worked on front-end and back-end development projects using agile methodologies, GIT and clean code.

I'm a responsible and organized person, I adapt easily to changes and always maintain a positive attitude. I like team work, I have analytical skills in project management and I pay attention to details.

Languages



+34 675 49 79 44

alexandragalarzag@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/magalarza https://github.com/MAlexGG https://malexgg.github.io/portfolio/

MARÍA ALEXANDRA GALARZA GALLARDO

Full Stack Developer | Architect

EDUCATION

Front-end web development, specialize in React.js (352h) | jan. - may. 2022 T Academy - Barcelona Activa

HTML5 y CSS3, Bootstrap and Sass, Javascript advanced and Typescript, errors and debugging, APIs, GIT and github.

React, unit tests y test-driven development methodologies, Redux. Transversal skills module, where various soft skills are worked on.

Full Stack web development (850h) | apr. 2021 - sep. 2021 Factoría F5 - Barcelona School

Front-end development: UX/UI wireframe, mocking and prototyping of interfaces, HTML5 and CSS3 advanced, atomic design, accessibility, Sass, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Javascript, Vue.js, Vuex, React.js Back-end development: OOP, Xampp, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Postgresql, APIs, Katas, Node.js, Jest, PHPUnit, Firebase, Heroku, clean code, MVC, hexagonal architecture.

Best practices and agile metodologies: TDD, SOLID, DRY, KISS, Kanban, Scrum. Version control system: GIT, Github, best practices in commits and branches.

Front End web development and agile metodologies (300h) | oct. - dec. 2020 Factoría F5 - Barcelona School

Agile Metodologies (Scrum and Kanban), interface development and user experience (UX/UI), HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, responsive design, mobile first, best practices, Github.

Master in Intervention and environmental management: people and society (75 ECTS) | 2017 - 2021 Universidad de Barcelona

Master in Sustainable intervention in the built environment (60 ECTS) | 2016-2017 Universidad Politécnica de Cataluña

Architecture degree (6000h) | 2001-2009 Universidad Católica del Ecuador

CERTIFICATIONS

- React.js essential | sep. 2021, LinkedIn Learning
- Ul advanced | sep. 2021, LinkedIn Learning
- UX advanced | sep. 2021, LinkedIn Learning
- Vue.js essential | aug. 2021, LinkedIn Learning
- SEO SEM | oct. 2021, Cyberclick
- Conservation Project Planning | apr. 2020, National Geographic Society
- Introduction to Conservation | apr. 2020, National Geographic Society
- Aproximation to the wood construction | jun. 2019, Centre tecnològic forestal de Catalunya
- QGis Geographic information system | jun. 2015, Mapping GIS
- Project Management | mar. 2015, Cámara de la Industria de la construcción
- Human relations oriented to give good service to the user | jul. 2012, MRL-Ecuador
- Cadastre for executives | jun. 2010, Instituto Agustín Codazzi
- Artistic painting, charcoal, watercolor, pastel and oil | 2003 2008, Tito Heredia
- Digital Photography | jan. 2006, Todoarquitectura.com

PARTICIPATION IN COMPETITIONS

- Hackaton Factoría F5 and Asperger Asociation Asturias | mar. 2021
- Open Source House Competition | may, 2010
- Lake Park, Municipio Metropolitano de Quito | oct. 2008

VOLUNTEERS

- Factoría F5 | oct. 2021 actually Collaboration for the pedagogic accompaniment for the promotions of 300h and 850h in Barcelona
- Architects Without Frontiers | oct. 2020 Collaboration in the round table topic: Human Scale in the city in Barcelona
- Catalunya La Pedrera Foundation | oct. 2018 mar. 2019
- School Accompaniment Program for children from 6 to 12 years old in Badalona ■ Un Techo para Ecuador | jul. 2006
- Roof construction program for indigenous communities in Riobamba

PEDAGOGICAL PROJECTS

The projects carried out in the bootcamps were developed as a team and individually, with agile methodologies and the following technologies were mainly used:























































WORK EXPERIENCE IN WEB DEVELOPMENT

| Factoría F5, Barcelona school | apr. 2022 - present

Co-trainer in full stack web development

Support for the training process for full stack web development bootcamps, applying agile methodologies, clean code and best practices. HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, PHP, Laravel, Java, SpringBoot, Scrum, Kanban, TDD, Unit Tests, Katas. Strengthen transversal skills aimed at job placement, additional training or entrepreneurship for groups in vulnerable situations.

Tikibike | may. 2021

UX/UI designer

Website for a company that offers bike routes in France designed in Figma.

Enfiladissa Macramé | feb. 2021

Front-end web developer

Website catalogue of macrame products developed in HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Javascript vanilla, responsive.

Lego Arquitectura | jan. 2021

Wordpress web developer

Website for an architecture company developed with wordpress using elementor.

l Área Metropolitana de Barcelona | apr. - dec. 2017

UX/UI designer

Collaboration with the IT department for the conceptual development of the geoportal of the department of Infrastructures.

Novatam C.E.M. | mar 2015. - sep. 2016

UX/UI designer

User interface and user experience of the municipal management system "e-GAD" based on a geographic information system.

Miski Chocolates | feb. 2012

Joomla web developer and content manager

Website of a shop that sold personalized chocolates, developed in joomla (currently out of production).

WORK EXPERIENCE IN ARCHITECTURE AND DESIGN

Área Metropolitana de Barcelona | apr. 2017 - jul. 2020

Architect

Maintenance of the GIS of transport actions. Updating of the document "Aproximació de les Infraestructures Metropolitanes". Drafting of the Manual of Styles for the Rondas de Barcelona. Generation of maps referring to traffic and tunnels. Collaboration in the drafting of urban landscape projects, 3d, photo montages, assistance in construction management and graphic design.

Novascotia S.A. / Novatam - C.E.M. | mar. 2015 - sep. 2016

Cadastral Project Manager

Conceptualization and development of the Municipal Management System "e-GAD" for the automation of municipalities in Ecuador, design of the corporate image of the public-private company NOVATAM-C.E.M.

Estudio A0 / Arq. Jaskran Kalirai | jun. 2016

Layout designer

Diagramming of urban - architectural sheets for the mass plan of the Huntley - Chicago project: three proposals "Factory Village", "Modern Main Street" and "Urban to suburban".

| Miski Chocolates | feb. 2012 - may. 2016

Graphic designer

Design of custom labels for chocolates using Adobe Illustrator.

Banco del Estado del Ecuador | aug. 2015

Technical trainer (20h)

Professional services to carry out the event called "Multi-purpose Cadastre, tool for Municipal development.

Estudio A0 / Arq. Jaskran Kalirai | aug. 2013 - sep. 2014

Architect

Architectural design Pichincha Bank Agencies, Páez - Gandara Residence, Corma Offices.

Empresa Pública Metropolitana de Servicios aeroportuarios, gestión de zona franca | jun. 2012 - jul. 2013

Alchilect

Supervision of the construction of the New Quito Airport contracted to the Luis Berger-Tahal company.

Dirección Metropolitana de Catastros | apr. - may. 2012

Architec^{*}

Supervision and quality control of the cadastral information survey carried out by Tecsult company.

Municipio Metropolitano de Quito, Administración Zonal Eugenio Espejo | apr. 2010 - jan. 2012

Appraisals and cadastres Team Leader

Direction and management of the decentralized department of appraisals and cadastres, a team made up of twelve people.

Arq. Patricio Endara Baca | nov. 2008 - mar. 2010

Architect

Architectural design of different residential and service projects.

REFERENCES

Architect José Alonso, Área Metropolitana de Barcelona, jalonso@amb.cat (Project leader)

Fullstack web developer Sergi Virgili, Factoría F5, sergi.virgili@factoriaf5.org (Fullstack web development trainer)

Fullstack web developer Manuela Grajales, NTTData, grajalesduquemanuela@gmail.com (Project jury in Factoría F5)